inside your computer are dozens of microchips
你的电脑里有几十个微芯片
with tens of billions of transistors
拥有数百亿个晶体管
you may know that these transistors are
你可能知道这些晶体管
the cornerstone of all technology
所有技术的基石
are manufactured in multi billion dollar factories
都是在数十亿美元的工厂里生产的
and are only a few nanometers
而且只有几纳米
meters in size
米
but what you may not know is that this
但你可能不知道的是
network of billions of transistors is
数十亿晶体管的网络是
actually organized a lot like Lego bricks
实际上组织得很像乐高积木
connected together in order to build a Lego set
连接在一起以构建乐高套装
such as this 7,541 piece Millennium Falcon
比如这个7541件的千年隼
in this video
在这个视频中
we'll explore how the transistors inside
我们将探索里面的晶体管
your computer are like Lego bricks
你的电脑就像乐高积木
what transistors actually look like
晶体管到底是什么样子的
how they perform basic logic
他们如何执行基本逻辑
and finally how 26
最后如何26
billion transistors are organized into
十亿个晶体管被组织成
the different sections of the CPU  so
CPU的不同部分，所以
let's dive right in
让我们开始吧
this video is sponsored by brilliant.org
本视频由brilliant.org赞助
let's begin with exploring Lego bricks and transistors
让我们从探索乐高积木和晶体管开始
in this analogy
在这个类比中
we'll equate one transistor to a
我们将一个晶体管等同于一个
single stud on a Lego brick
乐高积木上的单螺柱
on their own
靠他们自己
neither one does much at all
两个人都没做什么
however  when a few transistors are connected together
然而，当几个晶体管连接在一起时
they form a standard cell
它们形成一个标准细胞
which is the fundamental building
这是基础建筑
block of every CPU and GPU
每个CPU和GPU的块
similarly  multiple studs form a Lego piece
类似地，多个耳钉形成一个乐高积木
which is the building block for all Lego creations
这是所有乐高创作的积木
for example
例如
two transistors connected together
两个晶体管连接在一起
form an inverter standard cell
形成逆变器标准单元
four transistors connected together form a NAND gate
四个晶体管连接在一起形成一个与非门
and six transistors form an or gate
六个晶体管组成一个或门
there are many other standard cells built
还有很多其他的标准细胞
by connecting transistors together
通过将晶体管连接在一起
and similarly
同样地
there are a wide range of Lego pieces with
有各种各样的乐高积木
varying numbers of studs and shapes
不同数量的耳钉和形状
but before we explore some of the
但是在我们探索一些
more complicated standard cells
更复杂的标准细胞
we first need to understand how one of
我们首先需要了解
the simplest standard cells works
最简单的标准单元格工作
let's examine the inverter which is
让我们检查一下逆变器
analogous to a 1 by 2 Lego brick
类似于1乘2的乐高积木
its function is simply to take an input
它的功能只是接受输入
of a 1 and output a 0 or vice versa
1和输出0，反之亦然
this inverter has a logic symbol like this
这个逆变器有一个这样的逻辑符号
and the standard cells look like this
标准细胞看起来像这样
essentially
本质上
standard cells like this inverter are the real
像这个逆变器这样的标准电池是真实的
world physical structure of a logic gate
逻辑门的世界物理结构
and it's what you would see if you could
如果你可以的话，这就是你会看到的
open up and zoom into a nanoscopic view of
打开并放大到纳米视图
the processor in your smartphone  so
智能手机中的处理器，所以
let's see how it works
让我们看看它是如何工作的
at the bottom of the standard cell are two
标准单元格的底部有两个
transistors built on top of a silicon base
建立在硅基上的晶体管
we'll focus on one of these transistors
我们将集中讨论其中一个晶体管
which has been simplified a little bit
它被简化了一点
for the sake of this explanation
为了这个解释
inside this transistor are a few key parts
这个晶体管里面有几个关键部件
the gate  the channel
通道的大门
and the dielectric
和电介质
which is a barrier that separates the two and
这是一个分隔两者的屏障
prevents electricity from passing through
阻止电流通过
additionally on either side of the channel and
另外在通道的两侧和
above the gate are metal contacts connected to
栅极上方是连接到
vertical vias that are used to input and output
用于输入和输出的垂直通孔
electricity to the corresponding parts  so
相应部分的电力
how does this transistor work
这个晶体管是如何工作的？
well  when 1 volt is applied or input to the gate
当向栅极施加或输入1伏电压时
electricity is able to flow through the channel
电力能够流过通道
essentially connecting one side of
本质上连接的一边
the channel to the other side  however
然而，通往另一边的通道
when 0 volts is applied to the gate
当对栅极施加0伏电压时
electricity cannot flow through
电流无法通过
resulting in electrically separating or
导致电分离或
isolating the two sides of the channel
隔离通道两侧
a quick analogy is to think of the channel
一个简单的类比是想到渠道
and gate as a water faucet and handle
和门作为水龙头和把手
when the handle is turned on
当手柄打开时
water can flow
水能流动
and when the handle is turned off
当手柄关闭时
the water is stopped
水停了
the name of this transistor is an n type
这个晶体管的名字是n型
finfet due to its fin like shape
Finfet由于其鳍状形状
here's the symbol for a simple n type transistor
这是一个简单的n型晶体管的符号
and again  when 1 volt is applied to the gate
当1伏电压施加到栅极时
electricity can flow through the channel
电力可以通过通道流动
let's bring in a second transistor over here
让我们在这里引入第二个晶体管
which is the same Finfet shape
这是相同的Finfet形状
but functions a little differently
但功能有点不同
and is called a p type transistor
被称为p型晶体管
specifically
具体地说
it's designed to operate in the exact opposite
它被设计成完全相反的操作方式
fashion where when 1 volt is applied to the gate
当1伏施加到栅极时的时尚
electricity cannot flow through the channel
电不能流过通道
and when 0 volts is applied to the gate
当对栅极施加0伏电压时
electricity can flow through
电流可以通过
using our water faucet analogy from before
使用我们之前的水龙头类比
this transistor is like a faulty water
这个晶体管就像有故障的水
faucet where when the handle is down
把手放下时的水龙头
the water is on
水开了
and in order to turn the water off
为了关掉水
you have to actively lift the handle
你得主动提起把手
this is the symbol for the P type transistor
这是P型晶体管的符号
and the circle on the gate
还有大门上的圆圈
indicates the inverted functionality
表示反转功能
now that we have two transistors
现在我们有两个晶体管
one N type and the other P type
一个N型，另一个P型
let's connect the gate between the two
让我们连接两者之间的大门
of them and merge the input gate contacts
并合并输入门触点
together into a single contact
合为一体
as a result  a single input voltage on the gate
因此，栅极上的单个输入电压
which can be either 1 volt or 0 volts
可以是1伏或0伏
travels to the shared gate and
前往共享门和
controls both of the transistors
控制两个晶体管
because the N type and P type
因为N型和P型
transistors are opposite of each other
晶体管彼此相反
when 0 volts is applied to the gate
当对栅极施加0伏电压时
the P type will allow electricity to flow
P型将允许电流流动
through the channel and is considered on
通过渠道并被考虑
and the N type will be off
N型将关闭
and then when 1 volt is applied to the gate
然后当1伏施加到栅极时
the N type and P type Finfet's flip to on and off
N型和P型Finfet的翻转打开和关闭
and the N type allows electricity to flow through
N型允许电流通过
while the P type doesn't
而P型没有
the next step is to bring in the power and
下一步是引入权力和
ground rails above the transistors
晶体管上方的接地轨
the power rail is at 1 volt
电源轨在1伏
and the ground rail at 0 volts
和0伏的地轨
and they always stay at 1 and 0 volts  next
接下来它们总是保持在1伏和0伏
we add some wires to the design
我们在设计中添加一些电线
and to do that we use the contact points
为此，我们使用联络点
and build vertical vias that connect both sides of
并建造连接两侧的垂直通孔
the transistor along with the power rails to a
晶体管与电源轨一起连接到
layer of wires called local interconnects
称为本地互连的电线层
the power rails
电源轨
vias and interconnects are simply wires made
通孔和互连只是电线
from conductive metals such as copper
来自铜等导电金属
tungsten or aluminum
钨或铝
and just carry electricity around
并随身携带电力
in intricate paths of wires
在错综复杂的电线路径中
let's add a label for the input
让我们为输入添加一个标签
which is the electrical wire that
哪个是电线
connects to the shared gate
连接到共享门
and a label for the output over here
和这里输出的标签
which connects to the local interconnect wire
连接到本地互连线
attached to a side of each of the two transistors
连接到两个晶体管的每一侧
now that we have a complete standard cell
现在我们有了一个完整的标准细胞
what happens when 1 volt is applied to the input
向输入施加1伏时会发生什么
well  1 volt travels down to the shared gate
井1伏向下传输到共享门
that controls both of the transistors
控制两个晶体管
and as a result
结果是
the n type transistor turns on
n型晶体管导通
and the P type transistor turns off
P型晶体管关闭
with the N type transistor on
开着N型晶体管
electricity can flow through its channel
电力可以通过它的通道流动
which results in 0 volts from the ground rail
这导致从地轨产生0伏电压
traveling through the local interconnects
通过本地互连
down a vertical via
垂直通道
through the channel of the N type finfet
通过N型finfet的通道
then back up a vertical via on the other side
然后在另一边备份一个垂直通道
across a separate section of local interconnects
跨本地互连的单独部分
and finally to the output
最后到输出
thus the input of 1 volt results
因此1伏的输入结果
in an output of 0 volts
在0伏的输出
at the same time
同时
because the same 1 volt input controls
因为相同的1伏输入控制
the P type transistor which is off
关闭的P型晶体管
no electricity flows through it
没有电流流过它
and this section of wire is isolated
而且这段电线是隔离的
so then what happens when 0
那么当0时会发生什么呢？
volts is applied to the input  well
电压施加到输入阱
the opposite happens
相反的情况发生
the P type transistor turns on
P型晶体管导通
and the 1 volt rail is connected through the local
1伏导轨通过本地连接
interconnect wires and vias through the P types channel
通过P型通道互连电线和通孔
back up a vertical via and to the output
备份垂直通道并输出
thus turning a 0 into a 1
从而将0变成1
at the same time
同时
the N type transistor is off
N型晶体管关断
and this section of wire is isolated
而且这段电线是隔离的
one thing to note is that while these wires may look
需要注意的一件事是，虽然这些电线看起来
like they're floating three dimensional structures
就像漂浮的三维结构
all the empty spaces are in fact filled with
事实上，所有的空白空间都充满了
insulating material called dielectric
称为电介质的绝缘材料
this may have been a rather long explanation
这可能是一个相当长的解释
but truly understanding the basic function of
但真正理解的基本功能
the inverter standard cell is critical to
逆变器标准电池对
understanding the more complicated ones
理解更复杂的
such as this NAND gate
比如这个NAND门
this and gate
这个和门
or this exclusive or gate
或者这个独家或门
which we'll discuss in a little bit
我们稍后再讨论
let's now take a second and discuss some
现在让我们花点时间讨论一些
of the details that might be taught in an
可能会教授的细节
electrical engineering course
电气工程课程
here's the symbol for an inverter and its logic table
这是逆变器的符号及其逻辑表
and again  an input of a 1 outputs a 0
同样，1的输入输出0
and vice versa
反之亦然
next  here's the schematic where you can
接下来是示意图，您可以
see the 1 volt power rail above
请参阅上面的1伏电源轨
and the 0 volt ground rail below
和下面的0伏地轨
and here are the two simplified transistors with
这里有两个简化的晶体管
the bottom 1N type and the top one a P type
底部1N型，顶部P型
the input to the gates is connected together  however
然而，门的输入连接在一起
we typically break them apart and
我们通常会把它们分开
label them with the same input name  next
接下来用相同的输入名称标记它们
the output is positioned in the
输出位于
middle of the two transistors
两个晶体管的中间
as a result  when 1 volt is applied to input a
因此，当1伏电压施加到输入时
the output is connected to the ground rail
输出连接到地轨
and when 0 is input
当输入0时
the output is connected to the power rail
输出连接到电源轨
now that we've thoroughly explored this inverter
现在我们已经彻底研究了这个逆变器
let's dive into some of the more
让我们深入了解更多
complicated standard cells
复杂标准细胞
such as these NAND and nor gates with four transistors
例如这些带有四个晶体管的NAND和nor栅极
the and and or gates with six transistors
带有六个晶体管的and和或门
and the exclusive or and exclusive nor
而排他的or和排他的nor
gates with 10 transistors inside of it
里面有10个晶体管的门
first however
然而首先
let's continue discussing how
让我们继续讨论如何
standard cells are like Lego bricks
标准细胞就像乐高积木
as mentioned earlier
如前所述
there's a wide range of standard cells built
我们制造了各种各样的标准细胞
by connecting together different numbers of
通过将不同数量的连接在一起
transistors using a local interconnects
使用局部互连的晶体管
and similarly
同样地
there's a wide range of Lego pieces built by
有各种各样的乐高积木由
connecting different numbers of studs in varying
连接不同数量的螺柱
configurations
构型
so  to continue our analogy
继续我们的类比
if a Lego stud is an individual transistor
如果乐高螺柱是一个单独的晶体管
and Lego bricks and pieces are standard cells
乐高积木和积木是标准细胞
then the equivalent to a Lego set is a macrocell
那么相当于乐高套装的是宏细胞
for example  here are 350 Lego pieces used to
例如，这里有350件乐高积木
build a Starfighter Lego set
构建星际战斗机乐高套装
and likewise
同样
here are approximately 160 standard cells connected to
这里有大约160个标准电池连接到
form a macrocell that can add two numbers together
形成一个可以将两个数字相加的宏单元格
in order to connect each of the
为了连接每个
160 standard cells together
160个标准细胞在一起
a higher layer of vertical vias and
较高层的垂直通孔和
wires called metal 1 or M1 is used
使用称为金属1或M1的电线
when we zoom in
当我们放大时
we can find the individual standard cells
我们可以找到单个标准细胞
all fitting between multiple rows of the 1
1的多行之间的所有拟合
volt power and 0 volt ground rails
伏电源和0伏接地轨
as you may have figured out already
你可能已经知道了
this circuit uses binary ones and zeros
该电路使用二进制1和0
and the input numbers that are added together
和加在一起的输入数字
are sent to this macrocell using 1 volt or 0
使用1伏或0发送到此宏单元
volt on these two sets of 32 wires
这两组32根电线上的伏特
and then the binary output is carried
然后进行二进制输出
along these 33 wires over here
沿着这33根电线
let's continue this analogy further
让我们继续这个类比
just like there are thousands of different Lego sets
就像有成千上万套不同的乐高积木一样
there is a wide range of different macro cells
有广泛的不同宏单元
some having thousands upon thousands
有些人有成千上万
of standard cells inside of them
里面有标准细胞
for example
例如
a more complicated function is multiplication
一个更复杂的函数是乘法
which takes in two numbers
它包含两个数字
multiplies them together
将它们相乘
and then outputs the result
然后输出结果
however to perform multiplication we need a
但是要执行乘法，我们需要一个
much larger macrocell such as this one which
更大的宏单元，比如这个
is built from 6,100 standard cells
由6,100个标准单元构建而成
the complexity of the 32 bit multiplication
32位乘法的复杂性
macrocell is similar to the complexity of this
宏细胞类似于这个的复杂性
Millennium Falcon Lego set built from around
千年隼乐高套装从周围构建
seventy five hundred Lego pieces
七万五百块乐高积木
one note is that macrocells are also called modules
一个注意事项是宏单元也称为模块
functional blocks
功能块
functional units
功能单元
or just blocks or units  so
或者只是街区或单位，所以
now that we've seen a couple of macrocells
现在我们已经看到了几个宏细胞
what's the next step up
下一步是什么？
well  multiple macrocells are combined into an IP core
好吧，多个宏小区组合成一个IP核
and then multiple IP cores are combined
然后组合多个IP核
into a core or hardware accelerator
进入核心或硬件加速器
and these elements are then
然后这些元素
combined into a complete chip
组合成一个完整的芯片
such as this processor
比如这个处理器
which can be found inside the CPU
可以在CPU内部找到
package mounted onto a motherboard
安装在主板上的封装
processors are incredibly complicated with tens
处理器非常复杂，有几十个。
of billions of transistors inside of them  so
里面有数十亿个晶体管
here's a little bit of insight into how they work
这里有一点关于它们是如何工作的见解
again using Lego
再次使用乐高
Lego pieces are pretty simple objects
乐高积木是非常简单的物体
for example
例如
this pile of Lego bricks may hurt when you step on it
这堆乐高积木踩上去可能会疼
but overall
但总的来说
it isn't that interesting or impressive  however
然而，这并不有趣或令人印象深刻
when you meticulously assemble
当你精心组装时
thousands of Lego pieces together
成千上万的乐高积木拼在一起
you can build an impressive Lego creation
您可以构建令人印象深刻的乐高创作
likewise
同理
an individual transistor might seem pretty mundane
单个晶体管可能看起来很平凡
and a standard cell or a basic logic gate that can
和一个标准单元或一个基本逻辑门
only flip a 1 to 0 isn't all that useful on its own
只有从1到0的翻转本身并没有那么有用
however
然而
the key is that when you have tens of thousands of
关键是当你有成千上万的
scientists and engineers assembling billions
科学家和工程师聚集了数十亿
billions of standard cells and logic
数十亿个标准单元和逻辑
gates together in what can be thought of
能想到的大门在一起
as a multi billion piece Lego set  well then
作为数十亿件乐高积木，那么
we get an integrated circuit
我们得到一个集成电路
capable of browsing the internet
能够浏览互联网
playing YouTube videos
播放YouTube视频
or running video games with incredible graphics
或者运行具有令人难以置信的图形的视频游戏
by the way  thus far we showed you the local
顺便说一下，到目前为止，我们向您展示了当地的
interconnect layer for the standard cells
标准单元的互连层
and one metal layer called M1
和一个名为M1的金属层
which is used to build small macro cells  in fact
实际上用于构建小型宏单元
CPUs use around 17 metal layers of wires
CPU使用大约17层金属电线
connected together to form the macrocells  IP cores
连接在一起形成宏蜂窝IP核
cores and other sections of the CPU
CPU的内核和其他部分
CPUs are incredibly powerful devices
CPU是非常强大的设备
but when you boil them down
但是当你把它们煮沸的时候
it's just a bunch of transistors and logic gates
只是一堆晶体管和逻辑门
connected together using kilometers of wires
用千米长的电线连接在一起
Throughout this video we've assumed that you
在整个视频中，我们假设你
have a basic understanding of logic gates
对逻辑门有基本的了解
but if you want to learn more about how logic works
但是如果你想了解更多关于逻辑是如何工作的
we recommend you check out Brilliant Org
我们建议您查看Brilliant Org
the sponsor of this video
这个视频的赞助商
brilliant is an educational platform with
辉煌是一个教育平台
thousands of interactive lessons in math  science
数以千计的数学科学互动课程
programming
编程
data analysis
数据分析
along with two courses on logic
还有两门逻辑课程
Brilliant's mission is to create a
辉煌的使命是创造一个
world of better problem solvers
更好的问题解决者的世界
and every one of their courses is crafted with
他们的每一道菜都是用
a hands on problem solving approach that helps
帮助解决问题的动手方法
build understanding from the ground up
从头开始建立理解
we love to use brilliant because each of
我们喜欢使用辉煌，因为每个
their lessons is only 10 minutes long
他们的课只有10分钟
and their entire catalog can be accessed
他们的整个曲库都可以访问
using the brilliant app on your phone
使用手机上出色的应用程序
learning a little every day is one of the
每天学习一点是
most important things you can do
你能做的最重要的事情
both for your career and for your mental health
对你的事业和心理健康都有好处
consider this
考虑一下这个
if you were to use the brilliant app
如果您要使用出色的应用程序
instead of mindlessly scrolling
而不是盲目地滚动
in a couple of weeks you could build an in depth
在几周内，你可以建立一个深度
understanding of how AI and large language models work
了解AI和大型语言模型的工作原理
and then after that
然后在那之后
you could for example learn how to program in
例如，您可以学习如何编程
Python or see how quantum computers work
Python或看看量子计算机是如何工作的
with each lesson only 10 minutes long
每节课只有10分钟
it's a no brainer that you should delete
你应该删除这是显而易见的
addictive and time wasting apps and learn
令人上瘾和浪费时间的应用程序和学习
something new using the brilliant app on your phone
使用手机上出色的应用程序的新东西
you can sign up for free using the link
您可以使用链接免费注册
Brilliant Org Branch Education
辉煌机构支部教育
and for a whole month
整整一个月
you'll have full access to their
您将可以完全访问他们的
entire catalog of courses
整个课程曲库
if you like their content and decide to stick around
如果你喜欢他们的内容并决定留下来
the link will also save you 20%
该链接还将为您节省20%
off an annual subscription
取消年度订阅
you can also find this link in the description below
您也可以在下面的描述中找到此链接
so let's get back to exploring some of
所以让我们回到探索一些
the more complicated standard cells
更复杂的标准细胞
specifically
具体地说
we'll start with this NAND gate
我们从这个与非门开始
then the and gate
然后是和门
and then discuss the other types of logic gates
然后讨论其他类型的逻辑门
this NAND gate performs the logic
此与非门执行逻辑
of and followed by a not
of并后跟一个not
using the Lego analogy
用乐高来比喻
the NAND gate would be
与非门将是
equivalent to a 2 by 2 Lego brick
相当于一块2乘2的乐高积木
we'll move a little bit faster than
我们会比
our explanation of the inverter
我们对逆变器的解释
and start with the logic symbol
并从逻辑符号开始
truth table
真值表
and schematic
和示意图
to build a NAND gate
建立与非门
we use two P type transistors in parallel above
上面我们用两个P型晶体管并联
and two N type in series below
和下面串联的两个N型
the two inputs for the NAND gate are connected
与非门的两个输入连接
to one of each of the transistors gates and the
到每个晶体管的一个门和
output is in the middle of the channels
输出在通道中间
in order for the output to be a 0
为了使输出为0
both of the inputs need to be ones
两个输入都需要是1
thus turning both N types on and creating a
从而打开N种类型并创建一个
path from the ground rail to the output
从地轨到输出的路径
for the output to be a 1
输出为1
we need either or both of the P
我们需要其中一个或两个P
type transistors to be on
输入要打开的晶体管
thus creating a path from the 1
从而从1创建路径
volt power rail to the output
电压电源轨到输出
let's see how we turn this logic
让我们看看我们如何转变这个逻辑
into a physical standard cell
变成物理标准单元
here are the two P type transistors
这里是两个P型晶体管
above and the two N types below
上面和下面的两个N类型
as well as the power and ground rails
以及电源和地轨
to control these transistors
来控制这些晶体管
the two inputs labeled input a and input
标记为输入a和输入的两个输入
B are connected to the center of each of
B连接到每个的中心
the gates which span across one
横跨一个的大门
set of N type and P type transistors
N型和P型晶体管组
in order to build the P type transistors in parallel
为了并联构建P型晶体管
we connect the power rail to one
我们将电源轨连接到一个
side of each of the transistors
每个晶体管的一侧
and the output is connected in the middle
输出连接在中间
you can see that when either or both of
你可以看到，当其中一个或两个
these P type transistors is on
这些P型晶体管是开着的
which happens when a 0 is
当0是
applied to either of the inputs
应用于任一输入
then the 1 volt rail is connected through
然后1伏导轨通过
that p type transistor to the output
输出端的p型晶体管
as a result
结果
an input of 0 0
0 0的输入
0 1 or 1 0 yields an output of a 1  and again
0 1或1 0产生1的输出，并再次
these transistors are in parallel because either or
这些晶体管是并联的，因为要么或
both need to be on for 1 volt to travel to the output
两者都需要开启1伏才能到达输出端
next  let's look at the N type transistors which
接下来让我们看看N型晶体管
are placed in series with one another
彼此串联放置
to build this
建造这个
the ground rail is connected to one
地轨连接到一个
side of both of the transistors
两个晶体管的侧面
and the output is connected to the opposite side
输出连接到对面
therefore  for 0 volts from the ground rail to
因此，对于从地轨到
travel through these transistors
通过这些晶体管
both N types need to be on
两种N型都需要打开
which happens when both N types
当两种N类型都发生时
are connected to 1 volt  thus
因此连接到1伏
an input of 1 1 yields an output of a 0  again
1 1的输入再次产生0的输出
these transistors are in series because both need to
这些晶体管是串联的，因为两者都需要
be turned on to allow electricity to flow through
打开以使电流通过
one note is that thus far we've been showing the
一个注意事项是，到目前为止，我们一直在展示
power rail above and the ground rail below  however
然而，上面的电源轨和下面的地面轨
in the addition macrocell we showed earlier
在我们之前展示的附加宏蜂窝中
the power and ground rails are alternated
电源和地轨是交替的
and therefore half of the standard cells have
因此一半的标准细胞
the power rail below and the ground above
下面的电源轨和上面的地面
to accommodate this
来适应这个
the standard cell is flipped around with the P type
标准单元格与P型翻转
transistors on the bottom and the N type on top
晶体管在底部，N型在顶部
but it still works the same way
但它仍然以同样的方式工作
and if we rotate the camera  well
如果我们旋转好相机
it looks the same as before
看起来和以前一样
we're going to get to the other
我们要去另一个
logic gates in a second
逻辑门在一秒钟内
but first we want to say that this video script
但首先我们想说这个视频脚本
was actually one of the hardest to write
实际上是最难写的之一
in the first 28 drafts of the script
在剧本的前28稿中
we were trying to explain how standard cells work
我们试图解释标准细胞是如何工作的
and how logic gates are used to multiply two numbers
以及如何使用逻辑门将两个数字相乘
however
然而
we decided to move the lesson on how logic gates
我们决定转移关于逻辑门的课程
perform math into an entirely separate video
在一个完全独立的视频中执行数学
and focus this video on the design of standard cells
并将此视频集中在标准电池的设计上
as a result
结果
this video has taken close to 54 script revisions
该视频进行了近54次脚本修改
and six times I just threw out large
有六次我只是扔了大号的。
sections and restructured the whole script
部分并重组了整个脚本
so  we have one ask from you  the viewer
所以我们有一个观众的问题。
if you've enjoyed watching this
如果你喜欢看这个
video and Learned something new
视频并学到了新的东西
could you take just a few seconds
你能花几秒钟吗？
to write a quick comment below
在下面写一个快速评论
subscribe to the channel
订阅频道
like the video
喜欢视频
and most importantly
最重要的是
share it with a friend
与朋友分享
family member or colleague
家人或同事
we would greatly appreciate it
我们将不胜感激
thank you  let's next take a look at this and gate
谢谢你，让我们接下来看看这个和门。
here's the schematic along with the logic table
这是原理图和逻辑表
essentially an and gate is a combination of
本质上an和gate是
a NAND gate with an inverter tacked on
带有逆变器的与非门
let's take a look at the standard cell
让我们来看看标准细胞
here you can see the NAND gate with two inputs and the
在这里，您可以看到带有两个输入的NAND门和
output of the NAND gate being carried to the input of
与非门的输出被传送到的输入
the inverter with the overall output right here
总输出在这里的逆变器
as a result
结果
when we input two ones
当我们输入两个时
the output is also a 1
输出也是1
however  if either or both inputs are zeros
但是，如果其中一个或两个输入都是零
then the output is a 0
那么输出是0
the nor and or logic gates use very
nor和或逻辑门使用非常
similar setups to the NAND and and cells
与NAND和单元格类似的设置
a nor gate is simply a NAND gate but with two P types
非门只是一个非门，但有两种P类型
connected in series and the N types in parallel
串联N型并联
and then an or gate is a nor gate
然后an or gate就是nor gate
with an inverter tacked on
带有逆变器
pause the video to work out the logic
暂停视频以找出逻辑
exclusive or and exclusive nor gates are a little
独占或和独占也不是门有点
more complicated and require a total of 10
更复杂，总共需要10个。
transistors each because the logic needs to
每个晶体管，因为逻辑需要
account for only one of the inputs being on
只考虑一个输入
here's the standard cell for an exclusive or gate
这是独占或门的标准单元
we'll spend a few seconds flying around
我们会花几秒钟飞来飞去
it and showing the different layers  so
它并显示不同的层，所以
see if you can draw a schematic
看看你能不能画出示意图
and work out how it works
并弄清楚它是如何工作的
next  here's the corresponding schematic
接下来是相应的示意图
and then here's what it looks like
这是它看起来的样子
with an input of 1 and zero
输入为1和0
and then here it is with an input of 0 and 0
然后这里是输入为0和0
and then an input of 1 and one
然后输入1和1
when we look at an exclusive nor gate
当我们看到一个排他性的门时
we see that it's rather similar
我们看到它相当相似
just with the series and parallel N type
只需串联和并联N型
and P type transistors flipped around
和P型晶体管翻转过来
so one question is how do we make
所以一个问题是我们如何让
an and gate with 3 inputs
具有3个输入的an和gate
what about an exclusive or gate with 4 inputs
有4个输入的独占或门呢？
let's end this lesson by discussing a few
让我们通过讨论几个来结束这节课
important technical details and notes
重要的技术细节和说明
the first is that this circuit is called a
第一个是这个电路叫做a
complementary metal oxide semiconductor or CMOS circuit
互补金属氧化半导体或互补式金属氧化物半导体电路
this is due to the two types of transistors N type
这是由于两种类型的晶体管N型
and P type functioning opposite each other
和P型功能相反
these circuits have a high noise tolerance
这些电路具有很高的噪声容限
and low power consumption because one of the
和低功耗，因为其中一个
pairs of transistors is always off
成对的晶体管总是关闭
and if designed correctly
如果设计正确
there is never a path between the 1
1之间永远没有路径
volt rail and the ground rail
伏轨和地轨
the second note is that although the explanation for
第二个注意事项是，虽然对
how an inverter works took around 10 minutes in
逆变器的工作原理大约需要10分钟
actuality it physically takes just a few picoseconds
实际上，它只需要几皮秒。
or 10 to the negative 12 seconds between the input
或10到负12秒之间的输入
changing from 0 to 1 volt to the gates
从0到1伏切换到栅极
and then for the transistors to change their states
然后让晶体管改变它们的状态
and then for 0 volts from the ground
然后离地0伏
rail to travel to the output
导轨到输出端
with each standard cell taking a few
每个标准细胞需要几个
picoseconds to complete its logic
皮秒完成其逻辑
the multiplication macrocell
乘法宏单元
with over 6,000 standard cells
拥有超过6,000个标准单元
takes around 150 to 200 picoseconds between the
大约需要150到200皮秒
inputs coming in and all the standard cells
输入和所有标准单元
completing their logic and changing their states
完成他们的逻辑并改变他们的状态
to yield the correct value on the output wires
在输出线上产生正确的值
the third note is that transistors
第三个注意事项是晶体管
are incredibly complicated
非常复杂
for example
例如
most finfet are built from multiple fins in
大多数finfet都是由多个鳍构建的
order to improve electrical characteristics
改善电气特性
if you're wondering how
如果你想知道
transistors are made or how they work
晶体管是如何制造的或者它们是如何工作的
well  we're planning multiple videos that will
好吧，我们正在计划多个视频
explore transistor manufacturing
探索晶体管制造
transistor physics
晶体管物理学
why CMOS circuits use P type
为什么互补式金属氧化物半导体电路使用P型
transistors above and N types below
上面的晶体管和下面的N种
and the evolution and future of transistor design
以及晶体管设计的演变和未来
subscribe so you don't miss it
订阅，这样你就不会错过了。
the final note is that we'd like to give a shout
最后一个音符是我们想喊一声
out to Matt Venn who is vital in helping us get
给马特·维恩，他对帮助我们
these accurate standard cell layouts
这些精确的标准单元布局
he runs the zero to ASIC Course YouTube channel
他经营零到ASIC课程YouTube频道
and we recommend you check it out if you want to
如果你愿意，我们建议你去看看。
learn more about integrated circuit design
了解有关集成电路设计的更多信息
additionally
另外
he runs a service called Tiny Tape Out
他经营一个叫Tiny Tape Out的服务
which allows you to manufacture
它允许您制造
your own integrated circuit
你自己的集成电路
we're thankful to all our Patreon and YouTube
我们感谢我们所有的Patreon和YouTube
membership sponsors for supporting our videos
支持我们视频的会员赞助商
if you want to financially support our work
如果你想资助我们的工作
you can find the links in the description below
您可以在下面的描述中找到链接
this is branch education
这是分支教育
and we create 3d animations that dive deeply into
我们制作3d动画，深入研究
the technology that drives our modern world
驱动我们现代世界的技术
watch another branch video by
观看另一个分支视频
clicking one of these cards
点击其中一张卡片
or click here to subscribe
或点击这里订阅
thanks for watching to the end
感谢收看到最后